Don't mess with the hat.
The Cat in the Hat is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Bo Welch.
During a rainy day, and while their mother is out, Conrad and Sally, and
their pet fish, are visited by the mischievous Cat in the Hat.
Fun soon turns to mayhem, and the siblings must figure out
how to rid themselves of the maniacal Cat.
The Cat, played by Mike Myers.
Sally Walden, played by Dakota Fanning.
Conrad Walden, played by Spencer Breslin.
Joan Walden, played by Kelly Preston.
Larry Quinn, played by Alec Baldwin.
Mrs. Kwan, played by Amy Hill.
The Cat in the Hat (also known as Dr.
Seuss' The Cat in the Hat) is a 2003 American fantasy
comedy film based on the 1957 book by Dr.
The film stars Mike Myers as the Cat in the Hat, alongside Alec
Baldwin, Kelly Preston, Dakota Fanning, and Spencer Breslin.
Directed by Bo Welch and written by Alec Berg, David Mandel, and Jeff Schaffer, it follows siblings Sally and Conrad Walden getting paid a visit
by the Cat in the Hat, who plans to lighten up their rainy day with fun activities, while their mother Joan is at the office.
All the while, Larry Quinn, the Walden's sleazy next-door neighbor, plans to send
Conrad to military school and mooch off of Joan for her wealth.
Produced by Imagine Entertainment, The Cat in the Hat premiered in Universal City, California, on November 8, 2003, and was released
in theaters in the United States on November 21 by Universal Pictures, and internationally by DreamWorks Pictures.
The film received overwhelmingly negative reviews from critics and was a box-office
disappointment, grossing $134 million worldwide on a budget of $109 million.
It was nominated for ten awards at the 24th Golden Raspberry
Awards, including Worst Picture and Worst Director.
The negative reception of the film led to Seuss's widow, Audrey Geisel, prohibiting any further live-action
adaptations of her husband's books, including a planned sequel based on The Cat in the Hat Comes Back.
An animated readaptation is scheduled for release on November 6, 2026.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
chaos, cat, boredom, surrealism.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.